





Summary

Jump to Section

3 years of relevant experience in building business processes for clients, majorly Banking Domain in EMEA Region.

Actively using Core Java, JavaScript and RDBMS to build client requirement inside the core web application.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

Basic knowledge of Web Framework like JFS (RichFaces).

Closely interacting with Business Analysts to build core functionalities, business calculations and validations to support end user in quick and error free processing.

Responsible for complete Lifecycle of application from development to User acceptance and finally deploying into production and maintenance. Travelled to Ghana for SIT, UAT and Product Training of my last project. Successfully delivered onsite support and training to business users

Work Experience

- Newgen Softwares as Senior Software Engineer-IT Mar 2019 to Till Date
 - 1. Have been working on end to end development of business processes using Newgen Product suite.
 - 2.Built custom requirements in the system using Java and JS
 - 3. Integrated with third party systems like Core banking, Credit bureau etc. 4. Accomplished complete life cycle of project including onsite travel to Africa for client training and system handover.
 - 5. Been leading a team of 3 People, mentoring and training them to take up application development independently.
- Newgen Software Technologies as Software Engineer Jan 2017 to Jul 2019
 - 1. Have been part of full scale development of L1 business process designs.
 - 2. Trained to build custom forms on JSF(Rich Faces).
 - 3.Learnt about the Newgen Java based backend framework.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from the northcap university in 2017

^ Back to Top

1

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

II SKIIIS

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Core JAVA, JSP,JAX-WS		
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON		
Spring, Reflections, Soap		
SQL Server, Oracle 12g		
Jboss EAP, WebLogic		
Edipse, SQL Developer ,Bugzilla		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Projects

Project Title: FBN Account Opening Portal

Client: First Bank Nigeria Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Noida Role: Sr. Programmer

Duration: Jun 2020 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Java, Core Java, Javascript, Oracle, Websphere,

Project Details: Collaborating with the bank and end customers to finalize the UI/UX Using product suite and Custom CSS to design user friendly and attractive interface. Actively participating in daily review calls, integration study and application flow

leading a team of 3 to deliver the solution as per customer expectations in the planned time frame.

Project Title: PRUDENTIAL BANK EDMS IMPL. | Ghana

Client: Prudential Bank Ghana

Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Ghana Role: Sr. Programmer Duration: Feb 2020 - Jun 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Team Size: 4

Skill Used: Java, Web Services, SQL Server, JBoss,

Project Details: Built an enterprise level document management system for the bank using Newgen product suite and custome code on Java. JS. Extensively conducted onsite training and lecture programs with the bank's IT team on the product to enable them scale the system as per their needs

Project Title: Emirates Development Bank | Dubai

Client: Emirates Development Bank

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Noida

Role: Sr. Programmer

Duration: Feb 2019 - Jan 2020
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Java, Javascript, Web Services, Jboss Application Server,

Project Details: Developed the complete interface, back end process and DB Schema for the bank's Retail Loan Lending system. Built complex calculation logic, credit policy and scoring rules as per bank's guidelines in Java. Handled multiple SOAP based integration services with the core banking system and credit bureau.

Project Title: GCB CPC Implementation | Ghana

Client: GCB Bank

Nature of Employment: Full TimeDuration: Apr 2018 - Jan 2019Project Location: GhanaOnsite / Offsite: OnsiteRole: ProgrammerTeam Size: 3

Skill Used: java, Javascript, HTML,

Project Details: Developed the complete Account Opening and Account Maintenance modules for the client using product suite and custom coding backed logic in

Java and ultimately integrating with core banking system through web services to push all the information in the system. Participated in the complete life cycle from development to maintenance. Traveled to Ghana for the UAT and post production activities of the system.

Project Title: Abu Dhabi Finance | Abu Dhabi

Client: Abu Dhabi Finance Nature of Employment: Full

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: Noida
Programmer

Duration: Mar 2017 - Apr 2018
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: Core Java, Javascript,

Project Details: Completed OTJ training of Newgen products. Gained familiarity with the Newgen's development cycle. Took complete hand holding of a service request management module building the front end design, basic end user validations and custom logic. Supported the team in the SIT, UAT and Go-live phase of the project.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.